Guide to the Military Order of Foreign Wars of the United States, New York Commandery Records 1894-2012 (bulk 1894-1960s) MS 3201
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Digitized Material, 1894-2012 (bulk 1894-1960s); 73.7 Gigabytes 25,901 files (273 folders)
  - Applications Ledger 807 thru 901, 1.74 Gigabytes 608 files (Digital-folder 10)
  - Applications Ledger 902 thru 1000, 1.96 Gigabytes 675 files (Digital-folder 11)
  - Applications Ledger 1001 thru 1100, 1.91 Gigabytes 689 files (Digital-folder 12)
  - Applications Ledger 1101 thru 1200, 1.72 Gigabytes 601 files (Digital-folder 13)
  - Applications Ledger 1201 thru 1300, 1.68 Gigabytes 583 files (Digital-folder 14)
  - Applications Ledger 1301 thru 1400, 1.82 Gigabytes 641 files (Digital-folder 15)
  - Applications Ledger 1401 thru 1450, 1.19 Gigabytes 425 files (Digital-folder 16)
  - Applications Ledger 1451 thru 1500, 1.26 Gigabytes 441 files (Digital-folder 17)
  - Applications Ledger 1501 thru 1550, 1.23 Gigabytes 433 files (Digital-folder 18)
  - Applications Ledger 1551 thru 1600, 1.23 Gigabytes 430 files (Digital-folder 19)
  - Applications Ledger 1601 thru 1650, 1.18 Gigabytes 404 files (Digital-folder 20)
  - Applications Ledger 1651 thru 1750, 1.92 Gigabytes 657 files (Digital-folder 21)
  - Artwork 1923, 14 Megabytes 7 files (Digital-folder 22)
  - Constitution Typewritten Working Draft (Shoot 1), 57.4 Megabytes 17 files (Digital-folder 23)
  - Constitution Typewritten Working Draft (Shoot 2), 62.3 Megabytes 21 files (Digital-folder 24)
  - Docs 1897, 29.5 Megabytes 18 files (3 folders) (Digital-folder 25)
    Subfolder names: Committee Letter 30JUNE1897; LTC J. Abert Bio Sketch 1897; Minutes Special Mtg 1897
  - Docs 1898, 32.5 Megabytes 20 files (3 folders) (Digital-folder 26)
    Subfolder names: Annual Meeting 1898; Meeting 18DEC1898; Meeting 28NOV1898
  - Docs 1899, 28.5 Megabytes 18 files (4 folders) (Digital-folder 27)
    Subfolder names: Minutes Annual Meeting 1899; Nom Com NOV1899; Secretary Report DEC1899; Special Meeting DEC1899
  - Docs 1900, 58.8 Megabytes 37 files (5 folders) (Digital-folder 28)
    Subfolder names: Council Minutes Annual Mtg 13DEC1900; Meeting 5DEC1900; Minutes Annual Meeting 1900; Nom Com NOV1900; Sec Report Annual Mtg 13DEC1900
  - Docs 1901, 29 Megabytes 18 files (5 folders) (Digital-folder 29)
    Subfolder names: Annual Mtg 12DEC1901; Proxy Vote 12DEC1901; Sec Report 12DEC1901; Treasurer Rpt 10DEC1900-1901; Treasurers List 12DEC1901
  - Docs 1902, 34.3 Megabytes 21 files (3 folders) (Digital-folder 30)
    Subfolder names: Annual Mtg 11DEC1902; Member Roster 1APR1902; Sec Rpt Annual Mtg 11DEC1902
  - Docs 1903, 80.8 Megabytes 51 files (10 folders) (Digital-folder 31)
    Subfolder names: Ann Mtg Announce 1903; Annual Mtg 10DEC1903; Correspondence 1903; Council Report 10DEC1903; Council Rpt 10DEC1903; Member Roster 10DEC1903; Member Roster 12DEC1903; Report 10DEC1903; Sec Rpt Annual Mtg 10DEC1903; Sec Rpt ANnual Mtg Copy 10DEC1903
  - Docs 1904, 29.7 Megabytes 19 files (4 folders) (Digital-folder 32)
    Subfolder names: Council Rpt Ann Mtg 8DEC1904; Minutes Ann Mtg 8DEC1904; Sec Rpt Ann Mtg 8DEC1904; Sec Rpt Ann Mtg 8DEC1904 Copy
  - Docs 1905, 100 Megabytes 61 files (9 folders) (Digital-folder 33)
    Subfolder names: Annual Mtg 14DEC1905; Convention Speeches 12APR1905; Correspondence 1905; Council Rpt Ann Mtg 14DEC1905; Sec Report 14DEC1905
  - Docs 1962, 8.48 Megabytes 5 files (1 folder) (Digital-folder 34)
    Subfolder name: Council Mtg NOV 1962
  - Early National Constitution, 32.2 Megabytes 21 files (Digital-folder 35)
  - Institution Document Handwritten Version, 124 Megabytes 35 files (Digital-folder 36)
  - Institution Documents Typewritten, 73.8 Megabytes 28 files (Digital-folder 37)
  - Life Sketch LT Michael Moore, 11.1 Megabytes 4 files (Digital-folder 38)
  - List of Members 1 thru 1746 Ledger, 629 Megabytes 171 files (Digital-folder 39)
    The List of Members (Companions) Ledger is in digital format only (JPG and PDF). There is no accompanying paper copy. The original complete Membership Ledger is retained by the MOFW NY Commandery and lists members up to 1970. Member information beyond 1970 is not included so as not to possibly divulge living members' information.
  - MacArthur Medal, 404 Megabytes 143 files (17 folders) (Digital-folder 40)
  - Minutes Ledger 27DEC1894 thru 10DEC1903, 583 Megabytes 160 files (Digital-folder 41)
  - Minutes Ledger 27DEC1894 thru 23DEC1895, 298 Megabytes 87 files (Digital-folder 42)
  - Minutes of the Council Ledger 19JAN1895 thru 30APR1902, 762 Megabytes 218 files (Digital-folder 43)
  - Minutes of the Council Typewritten 8JAN1908 thru 16OCT1912, 292 Megabytes 94 files (Digital-folder 44)
  - Minutes of the Council Typewritten 24SEP1902 thru 5DEC1907, 336 Megabytes 99 files (Digital-folder 45)
  - Minutes of the Council Typewritten 29JAN1913 thru 5APR1916, 173 Megabytes 54 files (Digital-folder 46)
  - Minutes Typewritten 6DEC1919 thru 12JAN1922, 343 Megabytes 106 files (Digital-folder 47)
  - Misc. Historic Documents, 37.4 Megabytes 15 files (4 folders) (Digital-folder 48)
    Subfolder names: 100th Anniversary 1994; Mayor R. Giuliani Letter 1994; MOFW Honorary Members; NY State Law 22APR1896
  - NY Commandery Certificate of Incorporation, 82.9 Megabytes 29 files (Digital-folder 49)
  - NY Commandery History (06JAN2021), 507 Megabytes 209 files (Digital-folder 50)
    This document is in digital format only (JPG and PDF). There is no accompanying paper copy.
  - NY Commandery Name Change Document, 37.2 Megabytes 13 files (Digital-folder 51)
  - Photographs 06JAN2021, 468 Megabytes 229 files (15 folders) (Digital-folder 52)
    Subfolder names: 80th Ann Proclamation; CPT Roger Donton; European Commandery Dinner; GEN Drum Retirement Dinner; MOFW #1955; MOFW 21FEB2008; Annual Mtg 20APR1995; Companions Unnumbered; Dinner 11DEC1940; Dinner 15JAN1974; Dinner NOV 1990; Dinner Nov 1994; Medals; Mid-1970s; NY Charter